Has James Bond finally met his match?
A View to a Kill is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by John Glen.
A newly-developed microchip designed by Zorin Industries for the British Government that can survive the
electromagnetic radiation caused by a nuclear explosion has landed in the hands of the KGB.
James Bond must find out how and why.
His suspicions soon lead him to big industry leader Max Zorin who forms a plan to destroy his only
competition in Silicon Valley by triggering a massive earthquake in the San Francisco Bay.
James Bond, played by Roger Moore.
Stacey Sutton, played by Tanya Roberts.
Max Zorin, played by Christopher Walken.
May Day, played by Grace Jones.
Tibbett, played by Patrick Macnee.
Scarpine, played by Patrick Bauchau.
A View to a Kill is a 1985 spy film, the fourteenth in the James Bond series produced by Eon Productions,
and the seventh and final appearance of Roger Moore as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
Although the title is adapted from Ian Fleming's 1960 short story "From a
View to a Kill", the film has an entirely original screenplay.
In A View to a Kill, Bond is pitted against Max Zorin (played by Christopher
Walken), who plans to destroy California's Silicon Valley.
The film was produced by Albert R.
Broccoli and Michael G.
Wilson, who also wrote the screenplay with Richard Maibaum.
It was the third James Bond film to be directed by John Glen, and
the last to feature Lois Maxwell as Miss Moneypenny.
Despite receiving negative reviews from critics, who criticised the ageing Moore's
performance, and Moore's own dislike of the film, it was a commercial success.
The Duran Duran theme song "A View to a Kill" performed well in the charts, becoming the only Bond theme song to
reach number one on the Billboard Hot 100 and earning a Golden Globe nomination for Best Song.
The film was followed by The Living Daylights in
1987, with Timothy Dalton playing Bond.
The film explores themes of london, england,
helicopter, fire, drug abuse, france.
The tone is intense.